[{"id":1,"question":"Teams may encounter the need for \"technical\" user stories. Who decides the priority of these?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"the Product Owner with help from Operations","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Tech Lead with help from the Product Owner","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Product Owner with help from the Tech Lead","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"the Tech Lead with help from Operations","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":2,"question":"What is the Scrum Master's role during the daily stand-up?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Congratulate the team on their great work.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Stand outside the circle of developers and listen for impediments.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The Scrum Master should not attend—this meeting is for developers only.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Ask each developer what they did since the last daily standup.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":3,"question":"Which factor should not be considered during Sprint Planning?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"the team's velocity","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the number of stories in the product backlog","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"the stories that are ready","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the team's capacity","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":4,"question":"A team member has been showing signs of great personal distress: crying at work, snapping at colleagues, having heated phone conversations. As Team Facilitator, what should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Give the team member space and time to deal with their personal issues.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Tell the others on the team that their teammate needs some emotional support.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Notify the team member's manager of your observations and ask the manager for help.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Ask the team member if they would like to talk about what might be going on with them personally.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":5,"question":"Which statement describes the flow of work in the Scaled Agile Framework?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It is a \"push\" system.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is \"push\" at the top and \"pull\" at the bottom.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is a \"pull\" system.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is neither \"push\" nor \"pull.\"","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":6,"question":"What is the Product Owner's role in deciding the priority of work in the sprint backlog?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"None—the Scrum Master should prioritize the work in the sprint backlog.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The PO should prioritize the items in the sprint backlog.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The developers prioritize work unless they cannot complete it, in which case the PO should prioritize the remaining work.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"None—the developers should prioritize the work in the sprint backlog.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":7,"question":"The Scaled Agile Framework advocates that, if you measure only one thing, what should you measure?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"quality","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"predictability of delivery","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"cost of delay","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"return on investment","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":8,"question":"Why should you apply Weighted Shortest Job First?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"to maximize the return on investment","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"to determine the economic sequencing of the backlog","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"to visualize queue length","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"to fulfill a commitment to quality","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":9,"question":"You have classified the features in your backlog according to risk and value. Which features should the development team work on first?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"low-value and high-risk","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"high-value and high-risk","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"high-value and low-risk","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"low-value and low-risk","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":10,"question":"In the Scaled Agile Framework, what is the role of Enablers?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"They help extend the Architectural Runway.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"They connect vision to mission so the organization can be successful.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They support team building.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They remove the impediments to quality.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":11,"question":"Which outcome is not expected of a Sprint Review?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The team demonstrates its completed work.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team reflects on how to improve its performance.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Items in the backlog may be reprioritized.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Stakeholders give feedback about the work completed.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":12,"question":"What is not a technique used for splitting user stories?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"split by line-of-business","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"split compound user stories","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"split by alternative paths","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"split by interface","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":13,"question":"Who decides what the team will work on?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"the Scrum Master","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a self-organizing team","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"the Product Owner","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Product Manager","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":14,"question":"Which choice is not a Scrum value?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"focus","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"integrity","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"courage","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"commitment","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":15,"question":"What should happen if the Product Owner does not accept a story by the end of the iteration?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The team does not get credit for the story's points in its velocity calculation.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The story should be sliced to reflect the work completed.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The acceptance criteria should be adjusted to reflect the work completed.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The story should be shown to stakeholders for their feedback.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":16,"question":"Which statement is not true about the product backlog?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It is a list of work items that are behind schedule.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The items are maintained in priority order.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Anyone on the team can propose an item for it.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It includes all of the work to be done.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":17,"question":"A project has some major risks that the team wants to mitigate. What is the best way to monitor how well this effort is going?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"risk-based spike","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"risk-adjusted backlog","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"risk velocity chart","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"risk burndown graph","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":18,"question":"The VP of Engineering wants to start giving out a \"Team Member of the Sprint\" award to recognize a top performer in each group. What advice should you give this VP?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"This is unhelpful unless there has been recent employee feedback indicating that people feel underappreciated.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"This is a good idea as long as a different person is recognized in each sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"This is a good idea because awards can motivate people to do their best.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"This is unhelpful because it can destroy the team unity essential to achieving high performance.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":19,"question":"What is a difference between a team's task board and a Kanban?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"A Kanban has an explicit rule to limit WIP.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"A Kanban shows the backlog of work.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"A Kanban does not use a Definition of Done.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"A Kanban shows the status of the work items.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":20,"question":"The team complains that \"things have been falling through the cracks lately.\" What should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Ask the team's manager to make role assignments so the team can catch up.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Conduct a workshop to identify all of the things that need to be done and see who can help with each.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Refer to the team's RACI (Responsible, Accountable, Consulted, Informed) assignments.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Meet with the Tech Lead and Product Owner to try to identify what can be done.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":21,"question":"In Large-Scale Scrum, what is the recommended ratio of Scrum Masters to teams?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"One Scrum Master can support up to five teams.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Large teams should have two Scrum Masters.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"There should be one Scrum Master per team.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"One Scrum Master can support one to three teams.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":22,"question":"In the Cynefin framework, where are \"best practices\" most appropriate?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"in the Complex regime","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"in the Complicated regime","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"in the Chaotic regime","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"in the Obvious regime","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":23,"question":"A manager informs you that a developer from another team is between assignments, and she wants to place the developer on your team for a few sprints. What should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Explain to the manager that this will be disruptive to the team and ask that another assignment be found.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Explain the situation to the team and ask them to go with the flow.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Explain the situation to your manager and ask them to resolve it.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"When the temporary developer shows up, assign them to write documentation.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":24,"question":"The Product Owner complains to you that the team is not working hard enough and they need to increase their velocity by at least 50%. Which action should you not take?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Share the feedback from the PO and challenge the team to increase their velocity.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Ask the PO to explain the business context to the team.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Explain the impact of technical debt to the PO and the benefits of devoting some capacity to reducing it.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Hold a Value Stream Mapping workshop to identify and reduce waste.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":25,"question":"What is the name of the practice in which a cross-functional team collaborates intensively to develop a new product idea?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Hackathon","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Scrum at Scale","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Innovation and Planning","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Magnum Focus","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":26,"question":"The team's manager wants to attend the Sprint Retrospective. What should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Agree to the manager's request and notify the team.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Propose that the manager attend only every other retrospective.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Propose a different forum for the manager to meet with the team.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Ask the team if it is okay with them that the manager attend.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":27,"question":"Who is responsible for a Scrum team's performance?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"the team","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"the Scrum Master","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Product Owner","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Engineering Manager","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":28,"question":"Which statement concerning small, frequent releases of software is true?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The chance for rollback is high.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It typically requires a high degree of automation.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The administrative costs are high.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Backward compatibility may be jeopardized.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":29,"question":"What is the activity of clarifying and expanding user stories called?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"story point estimating","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Definition of Done","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"user story expansion","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"backlog refinement","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":30,"question":"Which strategy is preferred for development teams?","code":"`“…your job is to minimize output, and maximize outcome and impact.” - Jeff Patton`","reference":"`“…your job is to minimize output, and maximize outcome and impact.” - Jeff Patton`","choices":[{"text":"Optimize for most work done.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Maximize output and maximize outcome.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Maximize outcome while minimizing output.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Optimize for resource utilization.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":31,"question":"Which statement is true about the actor in a user story?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The actor does not have to be a specified role in the solution.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"There must be multiple personas for each actor.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The actor can be the system itself.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The system cannot be the actor.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":32,"question":"Which statement is true about Agile?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Agile requires a high degree of up-front planning.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Once the requirements are agreed to, the team can complete work.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Agile requires a high degree of discipline.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Agile works best when there is no contract.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":33,"question":"Which statement about burndown and burnup charts is not true?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Burndown charts show the work remaining to be done.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Burnup charts show the work completed.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Burndown charts are more useful than burnup charts.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Agile project management tools can produce these automatically.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":34,"question":"What is the name for the practice of going to see a process in use at the point of value delivery?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Six Sigma","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Gemba walk","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Total Quality Management","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Kaizen","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":35,"question":"When the team needs to make a decision, what is the best course of action?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Try to achieve concensus.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Take a vote and the majority rules.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Identify the person who is most knowledgeable and ask them to decide.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Let the most senior member of the team decide.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":36,"question":"Which action is something the Team Facillitator should NOT do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Embrace servant leadership.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Estimate story points.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Celebrate successes.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Remove impediments","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":37,"question":"A team needs to do research, design, prototyping. What is this type of story called?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Exploratory spike","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Backlog refinement","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Functional decomposition","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"R&D","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":38,"question":"Which statement about technical debt is true?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Technical debt is another name for bugs","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is at the Product Owner's description to allocate effort to reduce technical debt.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Adding technical debt should be avoided at all costs.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Technical debt is what the Product Owner owes to the developers if they work a lot of overtime to complete the sprint.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":39,"question":"Which statement about estimating is not true?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Absolute estimating is more reliable than relative estimating.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Relative estimating is more reliable than absolute estimating.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"In estimating, accuracy is more important than precision.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"In estimating, the effort is more important than the time required.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":40,"question":"Which ceremony should the Product Owner not attend?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"daily stand-ups","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Sprint Retrospectives","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"story point estimating","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"code reviews","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":41,"question":"Which task is not the Product Owners responsibility?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"estimating story points","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"refining acceptance criteria","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"giving feedback to developers about the user stories","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"demonstrating the work to stakeholders","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":42,"question":"Which choice is `_not_` considered during Sprint Planning?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"stories that meet the Definition of Done","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"team velocity","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"stories that meet the Definition of Ready","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"team capacity","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":43,"question":"You have noticed a pattern that the most interesting stories on the Sprint Backlog get started right away, and the least interesting stories languish or don't get done. What should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Use a lottery system assign each story.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Share your observation with the team and invite them to own and solve the problem.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"During story point estimation increase the points assigned to the least interesting stories so the team can boost their velocity.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Ask the Tech Lead to assign every story to a developer so they all get done efficiently and with accountability.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":44,"question":"What Agile practice best supports this principle: \"At regular intervals, the team reflects on how to become more effective, then tunes and adjusts its behavior accordingly\"?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Sprint Review","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Sprint Retrospective","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"daily stand-up","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Sprint Demo","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":45,"question":"On what are personas typically based?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"a sponsors or team members' personalities and traits","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"what the developers think is user friendly","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"real people, archetypal users, or composites of multiple users","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"descriptions of the product's functionality and use","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":46,"question":"Which statement describes Shu Ha Ri?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It is a library of coding patterns.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is a software testing strategy.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is a standard for interface design.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is a model for skill development and mastery.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":47,"question":"What does the Agile Manifesto indicate?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Responding to change is more valuable than following a plan.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Documenting requirements up front is more valuable than at the end.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Following the plan is essential for not going over budget.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Contract negotiation should be used to settle disputes.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":48,"question":"What is the main benefit of a working agreement?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It specifies core working hours.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It clarifies the reporting relationships on the team.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It defines the culture that the team aspires to achieve.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"It compiles everyone's information.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":49,"question":"What is the name of the information radiator that has multiple columns used to visualize the flow of work?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Work Flow Indicator","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Value Stream Map","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Story Map","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Kanban Board","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":50,"question":"Which is the best definition of story points?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"They are a relative measure of the effort needed to complete a story.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"They a measure of development time only, test time is considered separately.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They are a relative measure of the value of a story.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They are a measure of time to complete a story.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":51,"question":"What is a Scrum of Scrums?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It is technique for two or more teams working together coordinate their efforts.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"It is another name for the Scrum Master Community of Practice.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is an information radiator used to compare the velocity of several teams.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is the system demo for teams on the same release train.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":52,"question":"What is the Product Owner's role regarding the product backlog?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The PO must identify the intended users of the features on the backlog.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The PO is responsible for estimating the size of the total.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The PO must identify the dependencies that impact the backlog.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The PO decides what to include in the backlog and what to exclude.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":53,"question":"Why should a team do refactoring?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It assigns developers to other teams in order to eliminate personality conflicts.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It improves the functionality of the product,","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It recalibrates the success criteria for the product in the marketplace.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It improves the design, which can lead improved development efficiency and maintainability.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":54,"question":"Which choice is not a benefit generally associated with product demonstrations?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Learn about new requirements.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Learn feature suitability.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Learn about feature usability.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Learn about feature estimates.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":55,"question":"What is an information radiator?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"a list of KPIs for the team","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a list of overdue action items","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the task board","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"a highly visible display of key performance data","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":56,"question":"According to the Agile Manifesto, your highest priority is to _.","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"minimize change requests","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"satisfy the customer","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"get the job done on time","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"achieve the desired ROI","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":57,"question":"Product development organizations sometimes use descriptions of archetypal users and their values so that developers can design the system to meet their needs and wants. What are these descriptions called?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"actors","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"roles","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"agents","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"personas","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":58,"question":"The Product Owner is focused on testing a new system concept in the marketplace as quickly and inexpensively as possible. What is this first-generation product called?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"preproduction version","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"focus group demonstrator","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Generation 1 product","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"minimum viable product","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":59,"question":"To whom should the Product Owner report?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"the Quality Manager","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Product Manager","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"the Scrum Master","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Engineering Manager","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":60,"question":"What happens in Sprint 0?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The team delivers no story points in that sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team does regression testing prior to release to production.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team prepares to work on the product backlog.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"This is the time to inspect and adapt.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":61,"question":"What does the Definition of Done mean?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The story meets the INVEST criteria.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team has completed all of the work in its Sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The story has been handed off to the DevOps team.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team has agreed on the criteria for story completion.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":62,"question":"Which element is most important when describing your product?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"its cost","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"its licensing terms and conditions","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"its benefits","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"its features","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":63,"question":"Which choice best describes the Team Facilitator?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"a meeting scheduler","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a record keeper","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a project manager","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"an Agile coach","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":64,"question":"What is the name of the technique that divides a story into smaller pieces?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"mitosis","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"story slicing","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"disaggregation","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Divide and Conquer","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":65,"question":"A team member comes to you with a complaint about another team member. What should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Bring the complaint to the other person and try to resolve the issue.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Ask them to talk to the other person and try to work it.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Notify HR of the problem and ask them to handle it.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Invite both people a meeting and try mediate the conflict.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":66,"question":"What is the forming-storming-norming, performing model of team development known as?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"the Tuckman model","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"the Standard Team model","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Moore's Team Framework","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the Siebert model","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":67,"question":"What is the name of the ceremony in which you inspect the work completed during the sprint?","code":"`Sprint Retrospective: Reflect on the previous sprint, discuss what’s working well, what could be improved, and how to improve it to be more productive.`","reference":"`Sprint Retrospective: Reflect on the previous sprint, discuss what’s working well, what could be improved, and how to improve it to be more productive.`","choices":[{"text":"Sprint Retrospective","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Sprint Review","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Next-Sprint Planning","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Velocity Confirmation","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":68,"question":"Which choice best describes an Agile Release Train (ART)?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"continuous delivery","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"comprised of the teams within a program","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"DevOps Center of Excellence","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Scrum of Scrums","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":69,"question":"As an Agile coach, what should be your attitude toward your team members individual goals and motivations?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Understand them—try align personal motivations with the team's progress toward the project goals.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Nurture them-goals are the reason why people want to be at work.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Disregard them—personal views have no bearing on reaching the project goals.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Leverage them—use personal goals encourage team members raise their performance levels.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":70,"question":"Which phrase best describes an Agile team?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"self-directed","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"self-managed","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"self-sustaining","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"self-organizing","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":71,"question":"Which technique does not help prioritize the backlog?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"MoSCow","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Kano","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"WSJF","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Kaizen","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":72,"question":"What does the Definition of Ready mean?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The story has been tested end is ready for release to production.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The story is ready to be brought into a sprint.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The stakeholders are ready to discuss their requirements for story.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team has completed sprint 0 and is ready to work.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":73,"question":"Which is NOT a principle of the Scaled Agile Framework?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Centralize decision-making","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Apply systems thinking","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Take an economic view","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Unlock the intrinsic motivation of knowledge workers","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":74,"question":"Which statement concerning small, frequent releases of software is true?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The chance for rollback is high","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It typically requires a high degree of automation","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Backward compatibility may be jeopardized","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The administrative costs are high","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":75,"question":"What is the definition of capacity?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It is an inventory of the team's knowledge and skills that is used to plan the work that they do.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is the number of teams that a Team Facilitator can support concurrently.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is an adjustment to velocity, used in Spring Planning, to account for reduced availability of team members during the upcoming sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It is the maximum number of stories that will be allowed in a sprint.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":76,"question":"Which action is something the Team Facilitator should not do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Celebrate Success.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Embrace servant leadership.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Remove impediments","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Estimate story points.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":77,"question":"The team is complaining that they send request for clarification to the Product Owner, but these requests go unanswered. What action should you take?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"If there is a question about story, tell the developers to use their best judgement, avoid delay, and discuss the issue in sprint review.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Send a note to the Product Owner saying the delays in completing the work will be their responsibility, not the team's.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Develop a service-level agree (SLA) that defines certain response times for different types of request and ask the Product Owner to sign off on it.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Schedule a problem-solving session with the Product Owner and the other team members.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":78,"question":"Which choice is a pillar of Lean?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Frequent delivery of working software","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Respect for people and culture","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Courage","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Sustainable pace","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":79,"question":"Which statement best describes Agile, Lean, and Six Sigma?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"They are strategies for delivering customer value.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They were pioneered by Toyota.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They are strategies for discovering what the customer wants.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"They are derived from statistical process control.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":80,"question":"What is a user story?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"A description of what an actor wants to do in order to accomplish a goal","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"A description of archetypal users so the developers can make the solution user-friendly","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"A report from the field about a user's experience with the product","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The Agile term for a requirement","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":81,"question":"What is the expected output of a Planning Poker meeting?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The stories were discussed and each had a story point estimate assigned.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The team gave feedback to the Product Owner about the acceptance criteria.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team decided what stories should be developed within the same sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team made a preliminary plan for which stories will be completed in the next quarter.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":82,"question":"What is the definition of velocity?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The number of story points delivered during a sprint","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The average waiting time for a story on the sprint backlog","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The average wait time for a story to move from the product backlog to the sprint backlog","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The time it takes a developer to complete a story divided by its relative value","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":83,"question":"What is most important for a successful Product Owner to understand?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"The budget for the product.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The underlying technology of the product.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The development team's strengths and weaknesses.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The business context for the product.","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":84,"question":"Which statement about the Agile Manifesto is true?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"It was written via crowdsourcing and its authors are unknown.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It has been translated into dozens of languages and used around the world.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"It was written in 2001 and is obsolete.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"It was first published as part of Jim Highsmith's doctoral thesis.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":85,"question":"The team is not going to complete its Spring Commitment. As the Team Facilitator, what should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Ask the PO to extend the sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Advise the PO as soon as possible.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Report this at the Sprint Review.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Point out the reasons why and collaborate on solutions.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":86,"question":"When a user story is further decomposed, what are the elements called?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"technical tasks","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"actors and actions","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Who, What, Why","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"threads","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":87,"question":"What does collective ownership mean?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Every member of the team can make changes to any part of the code as necessary.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"If someone is at fault, then the whole team is at fault.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"The team shares equally in the profits that the product generates.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"The team, not the individuals, receive performance evaluations.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":88,"question":"According to the Agile Manifesto, how often should developers and business people work together?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"as often as needed","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"biweekly","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"daily","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"weekly","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":89,"question":"What do you call the practice of writing a test before the code is written?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"design for testability","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"test-driven development","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"unit testing","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"test then code","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":90,"question":"The team is not going to complete its Sprint Commitment. As the Team Facilitator, what should you do?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Ask the PO to extend the sprint.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Report this at the Sprint Review.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Point out the reasons why and collaborate on solutions.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Advise the PO as soon as possible.","answer":false,"code":false}]}]